<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>

  <HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef Abstract="true" Name="Cloning.UpdateFeatureBase">
    <modNameReadable>Biotech Cloning</modNameReadable>
    <modIdentifier>Dark.Cloning</modIdentifier>
    <linkUrl>https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2881790485</linkUrl>
  </HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef>

  <HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef ParentName="Cloning.UpdateFeatureBase">
    <defName>Dark.Cloning_0.2</defName>
    <assemblyVersion>0.2</assemblyVersion>
    <content>An overhaul of the cloning system that should have better compatibility and most importantly, includes a way to clone xenogenes.
|
|
|Save Compatibility:
|This update SHOULD be compatible with saves using the previous version.
|• Clones made with the previous version of the mod will have the Clone gene as the wrong gene type.
    ○ This should have no significant impact on gameplay aside from the fact that the clone's natural children will inherit the Clone gene, which may log warnings.
    ○ If you have issues with this, use dev mode to remove the Clone gene.
|• Embryos created with the previous version that have not been gestated yet will not inherit their clone data properly.
    ○ This includes embryos currently growing in a growth vat.
    ○ The entire system for clone inheritance was changed behind the scenes, pre-existing embryos will not have any clone data associated with them.
|
|

|img:updateimages/GeneProcessorLinking
|Build Gene Processors near the Clone Extractor to raise the maximum genetic complexity you can apply to new clones, just like the Gene Assembler.
|
|
|When extracting a clone embryo using the Clone Extractor, a new dialog will be shown where you can choose the xenogenes of the resulting clone.
|Clone Creation Dialog:
|img:updateimages/CloneCreationDialog_0_2
|Breakdown:
|• TOP: List of all genes to be cloned.
Includes:
  ○ Germline genes inherited from the donor
    ◦ These cannot be changed.
  ○ Xenogenes inherited from the donor
    ◦ Shown slightly darker and with a lock symbol.
    ◦ You may click any one of these to remove the entire xenotype's xenogenes.
    ◦ Removing one xenogene from the donor removes them all.
  ○ Xenogenes added from genepacks
|• MIDDLE: Xenogenes from the donor pawn's xenotype
  ○ By default, these will all be included in the top section, leaving this section blank unless you remove them from the clone.
|• BOTTOM: Genepacks stored in nearby gene banks
NOTE: Clicking on even one of these to add it to the clone's xenotype will cause the xenotype of the resulting clone to be a unique, new xenotype. This change is only undone if you back out of the Clone Creation Dialog and start again 
|
|You may choose to have the cloned pawn inherit all of the donor's xenogenes, or none of them. You cannot pick individual genes and choose from them.
You can, however, include xenogenes from genepacks in nearby gene banks, just like the vanilla Biotech gene assembler. Use this to design your perfect clone supersoldiers.
|If no additional xenogenes are added, the resulting clone will have the exact same xenotype as the donor pawn (A Hussar donor will result in a Hussar clone).
|
|
|As always, this mod is still a beta, report any bugs you encounter on the Steam workshop page.
Please read the mod description on the Steam Workshop, including the Known Issues list.
    </content>
    <targetAudience>AllPlayers</targetAudience>
  </HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef>
  
</Defs>